Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles B. Davenport Papers, 1878-1944; 43 linear feet (Box 1-97)
  - Johnson, Emory R. (Box 59)
  - Johnson, F. W. (Box 59)
  - Johnson, Herbert P. (Box 59)
  - Johnson, J. B. (Box 59)
  - Johnson, J. M. (Box 59)
  - Johnson, John W. (Box 59)
  - Johnson, Roswell H., 1897-1936; 5 folders (197 items) (Box 59)
    Botany and plant genetics; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Eugenics; Genetics; Graduate study; Human genetics; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1897-1905 (Box 59)
    - Folder 2, 1906-1909 (Box 59)
    - Folder 3, 1910-1920 (Box 59)
    - Folder 4, 1921-1927 (Box 59)
    - Folder 5, 1928-1936 (Box 59)
  - Johnstone, E. R. (Edward Ransom), 1909-1931; 75 items (Box 59)
    Eugenics; Genetics; Human genetics; Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution
  - Jones, Charles H. (Box 59)
  - Jones, Donald F., 1919-1935; 3 folders (Box 59)
    Editorial matters; Publication -- Genetics; Referee's report
  - Jones, E. N. (Box 59)
  - Jones, Frederick Wood (Box 59)
  - Jones, Harold E. (Box 59)
  - Jones, J. M. (Box 59)
  - Jones, L. R. (Box 59)
  - Jones, Mrs. F. Robertson (Box 59)
  - Jones, Paul H. (Box 59)
  - Jones, Ruth (Box 59)
  - Jones, Sarah V. H. (Box 59)
  - Jones, Townsend, 1901-1915; 61 items (Box 59)
    Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; International Congress of Zoology; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Jones, Walter R. F. (Box 59)
  - Jones, William E. (Box 59)
  - Jordan, David S., 1895-1926; 3 folders (124 items) (Box 59)
    Committee activities; Eugenics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Political issues; Requests for aid in finding positions; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution
  - Jordan, Edwin O. (Box 60)
  - Jordan, H. E., 1906-1931; 69 items (Box 60)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Human genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Jordan, Hovey (Box 60)
  - Jorenby, M. C. (Box 60)
  - Journal of American Institute of Criminal Law and Criminology (Box 60)
  - Journal of Calendar Reform (Box 60)
  - Journal of Experimental Zoology (Box 60)
  - Jucci, Carlo (Box 60)
  - Juday, Chauncey (Box 60)
  - Judd, Sylvester D. (Box 60)
  - Judson, Harry P. (Box 60)
  - Just, Günther, 1921-1930; 21 items (Box 60)
    Editorial matters; Eugenics; Human genetics; Political issues -- Germany
  - Kaempffert, Waldemar (Box 60)
  - Kahn, Otto H. (Box 60)
  - Kamenoff, Ralph J. (Box 60)
  - Kammerer, Paul (Box 60)
  - Kammeyer, H. Frazer (Box 60)
  - Karpechenko, G. (Box 60)
  - Karsner, Howard T. (Box 60)
  - Kawakami, Riiti (Box 60)
  - Kebreau, Frederick (Box 60)
  - Keeler, Clyde E. (Box 60)
  - Keen, William W. (Box 60)
  - Keep, Mabel Hazlett (Box 60)
  - Keith, Arthur (Box 60)
  - Keller, Arthur H. (Box 60)
  - Kellogg, James L. (Box 60)
  - Kellogg, John Harvey, 1912-1930; 4 folders (156 items) (Box 60)
    Anthropology; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; Eugenics; Genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1912-1914 (Box 60)
    - Folder 2, 1915-1916 (Box 60)
    - Folder 3, 1917-1922 (Box 60)
    - Folder 4, 1923-1930 (Box 60)
  - Kellogg, V. L. (Vernon Lyman), 1895-1929; 3 folders (92 items) (Box 60)
    Bibliographical matters; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Genetics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- First Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Zoology; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Russian politics and science; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Kelly, Fred J. (Box 60)
  - Kelly, Harry M. (Box 60)
  - Kelly, James P. (Box 60)
  - Kemp, Tage (Box 60)
  - Kenkel, Louis V. (Box 60)
  - Kennedy, W. J. (Box 60)
  - Kennelly, A. E. (Box 60)
  - Kenyon, F. C. (Box 60)
  - Keppel, Frederick P. (Box 60)
  - Key, Wilhemine M. E., 1901-1932; 3 folders (96 items) (Box 61)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Genetics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Publication
  - Kidder, A. V. (Alfred Vincent), 1926-1933; 2 folders (57 items) (Box 61)
    Anthropology; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Eugenics Record Office; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; National Research Council -- Committee activities; Recommendations -- Steggerda, Morris; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Kilgore, Eugene S. (Box 61)
  - Kimbrig, Ida F. (Box 61)
  - Kincaid, Warren C. (Box 61)
  - King, Cyrus A. (Box 61)
  - King, Helen Dean (Box 61)
  - Kingsley, J. S. (Box 61)
  - Kinkead, E. F. (Box 61)
  - Kirby, George H. (Box 61)
  - Kirkham, W. B. (Box 61)
  - Kislovsky, D. (Box 61)
  - Klee, Andrew (Box 61)
  - Klein, Annette (Box 61)
  - Klein, Irwin J. (Box 61)
  - Kleina, Mrs. Frank (Box 61)
  - Knibbs, G. H. (Box 61)
  - Knoblauch, G. W. (Box 61)
  - Knopf, S. Adolphus (Box 61)
  - Knorr, George W. (Box 61)
  - Knower, H. McE. (Box 61)
  - Knox, A. W. (Box 61)
  - Kofoid, Charles A. (Box 61)
  - Kohs, Samuel C. (Box 61)
  - Kollogg, Vernon L. (Box 61)
  - Koltzoff, N. K. (Box 61)
  - Komai, Taku (Box 61)
  - Kooiman, H. N. (Box 61)
  - Kopec, Stefan (Box 61)
  - Kopf, Edwin W. (Box 61)
  - Kornhauser, Sidney I. (Box 61)
  - Korosy, K. V. (Box 61)
  - Korschelt, E. (Box 61)
  - Kotsovsky, D. A. (Box 61)
  - Kraemer, H. (Box 61)
  - Kramp, P. L. (Box 61)
  - Krantz, F. (Box 61)
  - Kratz, George Davenport (Box 61)
  - Krauss, F. G. (Box 61)
  - Krauss, Wilhelm (Box 61)
  - Kreezer, George (Box 61)
  - Kreglow, Grover C. (Box 61)
  - Krieger, Paul (Box 61)
  - Kríženeký, J., 1925-1933; 2 folders (Box 61)
  - Krogman, W. M. (Box 61)
  - Krohne, A. (Box 61)
  - Kugelmass, I. Newton (Box 61)
  - Kunkel, B. W. (Box 61)
  - Kunz, George F. (Box 61)
  - Kuraz, Rudolf (Box 61)
  - Laanes, Theophil (Box 62)
  - Lacey, Louise E. (Box 62)
  - Ladd, W. S. (Box 62)
  - Laemmel, Rudolf (Box 62)
  - Laird, Donald A. (Box 62)
  - Lancaster, Ellsworth G. (Box 62)
  - Lancefield, D. E. (Box 62)
  - Landauer, Walter (Box 62)
  - Landschoof, Joseph A. (Box 62)
  - Landsteiner, Karl (Box 62)
  - Lane, Alfred C. (Box 62)
  - Lang, Arnold (Box 62)
  - Lange, Johan (Box 62)
  - Lange, Mathilde M. (Box 62)
  - Langfeld, H. S. (Box 62)
  - Langhans, Paul (Box 62)
  - Langley, S. P. (Box 62)
  - Lanman, Charles R. (Box 62)
  - Lapouge, G. de (Box 62)
  - Large, Thomas (Box 62)
  - Larrimer, W. H. (Box 62)
  - Larsen, Thomas A. (Box 62)
  - Larsson, Robert (Box 62)
  - LaRue, D. W. (Box 62)
  - Lasker, B. (Box 62)
  - Latcha, J. A. (Box 62)
  - Latham, Ethel L. (Box 62)
  - Latham, V. A. (Box 62)
  - Lathrop, Abbie E. C. (Box 62)
  - Lauppenberger, Herr (Box 62)
  - Laüprecht, E (Box 62)
  - Laurant, Dr. (Box 62)
  - Laurie, D. F. (Box 62)
  - Law, William A. (Box 62)
  - Lawrence, G. Alfred (Box 62)
  - Lawrence, Joseph S. (Box 62)
  - Layton, Warren K. (Box 62)
  - Leach, Henry Goddard (Box 62)
  - League of Free Nations (Box 62)
  - Leake, Chauncey D. (Box 62)
  - Leaming, Byron (Box 62)
  - Lear, Lester (Box 62)
  - Leathers, W. S. (Box 62)
  - Leavitt, Robert G. (Box 62)
  - Lebedeff, G. A. (Box 62)
  - Lechevalier, Jacques (Box 62)
  - Lechner, John (Box 62)
  - L'Ecluse, Mrs. Milton (Box 62)
  - L'Ecluse, Washburn and Co. (Box 62)
  - Lee, Blewett (Box 62)
  - Lee, Frederick S. (Box 62)
  - Lee, Joseph (Box 62)
  - Lee, Roger (Box 62)
  - Lee, Thomas E. (Box 62)
  - Lee, Thomas G. (Box 62)
  - Leersum, E. C. van (Box 62)
  - Leete, Mary (Box 62)
  - Lefevre, George (Box 62)
  - Legendre, W. C. (Box 62)
  - Legrain, Dr. (Box 62)
  - Lehmann, J. F. (Box 62)
  - Lehmann, Rudolf (Box 62)
  - Lehmann, Theodore A. (Box 62)
  - Lehrenkrausse, Julius & Sons (Box 62)
  - Leland, Waldo G. (Box 62)
  - Lemcke & Buechner (Box 62)
  - Lennehan, James D. (Box 62)
  - Lenz, F. (Fritz), 1923-1931; 27 items (Box 62)
    Eugenics; Human genetics; Political issues; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Letchworth Village (Box 62-63)
    - Buck, Elizabeth, 1935-1939 (Box 62)
    - Humphreys, Edward J., 1933-1941; 6 folders (342 items) (Box 62-63)
      Anthropology; Biographical and personal data; Human genetics; Letchworth Village; Publication; Research support
      - Folder 1, 1933-1934 (Box 62)
      - Folder 2, 1935 (Box 63)
      - Folder 3, 1936 (Box 63)
      - Folder 4, 1937 (Box 63)
      - Folder 5, 1938 (Box 63)
      - Folder 6, 1939-1941 (Box 63)
    - Kinder, Elaine F., 1935-1936 (Box 63)
    - Kirkbride, F. B., 1933-1934 (Box 63)
    - Levy, Matilda, 1936 (Box 63)
    - Little, C. S. (Charles S.), 1913-1936; 3 folders (214 items) (Box 63)
      Cytogenetics; Embryology, developmental genetics; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Letchworth Village; Recommendations; Research support
    - Misc. correspondence, 1933-1939 (Box 63)
    - Renfore, Olive, 1933-1936 (Box 63)
    - Research Council (Box 63)
    - Research Department (Box 63)
  - Leven, Dr. (Box 63)
  - Levin, Isaac (Box 63)
  - Levine, Michael (Box 63)
  - Lewinski-Corwin, E. H. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, C. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, Charles F. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, Edward R. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, Frederick T. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, Frederick W. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, Harry R. (Box 63)
  - Lewis, J. F. (Box 64)
  - Lewis, L. L. (Box 64)
  - Lewis, Mary (Box 64)
  - Lewis, O. F. (Box 64)
  - Lewis, Park (Box 64)
  - Lewis, Warren H. (Box 64)
  - Lewitsky, G. (Box 64)
  - Lichtmann, Sina (Box 64)
  - Lichtner, William O. (Box 64)
  - Licorish, R. F. (Box 64)
  - Liebhart, Joseph (Box 64)
  - Liebisch, Bernhard (Box 64)
  - Life Extenstion Institute (Box 64)
  - Life Magazine (Box 64)
  - Liggett, Mrs. Norma (Box 64)
  - Light, John H. (Box 64)
  - Lightfoot, Gerald (Box 64)
  - Lightfoot, Mrs. Dorothy Herndon (Box 64)
  - Lillie, Frank Rattray, 1898-1937; 5 folders (137 items) (Box 64)
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Displaced German scholars; Fellowships, assistantships; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; International Congress of Zoology -- First Congress; International Congress of Zoology -- Second Congress; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; National Academy of Sciences -- Committee activities; National Research Council -- Committee activities; Poultry genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; University of Chicago
    - Folder 1, 1898-1906 (Box 64)
    - Folder 2, 1907-1911 (Box 64)
    - Folder 3, 1914-1922 (Box 64)
    - Folder 4, 1923-1925 (Box 64)
    - Folder 5, 1926-1937 (Box 64)
  - Lillie, Ralph S. (Box 64)
  - Limerick, O. Victor (Box 64)
  - Lindbergh, Charles A. (Box 64)
  - Linders, F. J. (Box 64)
  - Lindgren, Carl C. (Box 64)
  - Lindsay, S. M. (Box 64)
  - Lindstrom, E. W. (Box 64)
  - Linfield, Harry S. (Box 64)
  - Linhart, G. A. (Box 64)
  - Link, George K. (Box 64)
  - Linton, Edward (Box 64)
  - Linville, H. R. (Box 64)
  - Lipa, J. (Box 64)
  - Lipshütz, Alexandre (Box 64)
  - Litschutz, F. S. (Box 64)
  - Little, C. C. (Clarence Cook), 1916-1934; 321 items (Box 64)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Mouse genetics; Poultry genetics; Publication; Research support; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Little, Charles S. (Box 64)
  - Livi, Livio (Box 64)
  - Livingston, Burton E., 1907-1930; 52 items (Box 64)
    Academic freedom; Bibliographical matters; Committee activities; Evolution; National Research Council; Philosophy of science
  - Lloyd, Francis E. (Box 64)
  - Lockman, Ruth (Box 64)
  - Lockwood, Charles D. (Box 64)
  - Lockwood, Helen (Box 64)
  - Locy, William A. (Box 64)
  - Loeb, Jacques, 1892-1919; 13 items (Box 64)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Physiology; Reviews
  - Loeb, Leo (Box 64)
  - Loeb, Louis (Box 64)
  - Loeb, William, Jr. (Box 64)
  - Loew, P. (Box 64)
  - Logan, Lorens (Box 64)
  - Loisel, Gustav (Box 64)
  - Lomax, Howell J. (Box 64)
  - Lommen, C. F. (Box 64)
  - Long, Harland W. (Box 65)
  - Long Island Railroad Company, 1904-1925; 2 folders (Box 65)
  - Long Islander (Box 65)
  - Longcope, Warfield T. (Box 65)
  - Longley, W. H. (Box 65)
  - Loomis, Seymour C. (Box 65)
  - Loos, Richard F. (Box 65)
  - Looss, W. (Box 65)
  - Lord, Ralph (Box 65)
  - Lorenz, Alice Barber (Box 65)
  - Lorimer, Frank W. (Box 65)
  - Lory, Charles A. (Box 65)
  - Lotka, Alfred J. (Box 65)
  - Lotsy, J. P. (Box 65)
  - Louisville and Nashville Railroad (Box 65)
  - Lount, Robert (Box 65)
  - Love, Albert G. (Box 65)
  - Love, Harry H. (Box 65)
  - Lovejoy, A. O. (Box 65)
  - Lovejoy, Owen R. (Box 65)
  - Low, Seth (Box 65)
  - Lowden, Frank O. (Box 65)
  - Lowe, V. H. (Box 65)
  - Lowell, F. L. (Box 65)
  - Lowenberg, K. (Box 65)
  - Lowry, Edith B. (Box 65)
  - Lucas, F. A. (Box 65)
  - Lucas, F. Colby (Box 65)
  - Luchaire, Julien (Box 65)
  - Luchan, Dr. von (Box 65)
  - Lumsden, David (Box 65)
  - Lundborg, Herman B., 1913-1936; 2 folders (55 items) (Box 65)
    Anthropology; Committee activities; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Lush, Jay L. (Box 65)
  - Lusk, Graham (Box 65)
  - Lute, Anna M. (Box 65)
  - Luther Burbank Society (Box 65)
  - Lutz, Anne Mae, 1904-1921; 6 folders (102 items) (Box 65)
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Genetics of plants -- Oenothera
    - Folder 1, 1904 Jan. - April (Box 65)
    - Folder 2, 1904 May - June (Box 65)
    - Folder 3, 1905-1908 (Box 65)
    - Folder 4, 1909 (Box 65)
    - Folder 5, 1910-1911 (Box 65)
    - Folder 6, 1912-1921 (Box 65)
  - Lydenberg, Harry M. (Box 65)
  - Lyle, W. G. (Box 65)
  - Lynch, Charles (Box 65)
  - Lynch, Ruth S. (Box 65)
  - Lyndon, Arnold (Box 65)
  - Lyon, Charles J. (Box 65)
  - Lyon, E. P. (Box 65)
  - Maas, Otto (Box 65)
  - Macaulay, T. B. (Box 65)
  - Mac-Auliffe, Léon (Box 65)
  - MacBride, E. W. (Box 65)
  - MacCaughey, Vaughan (Box 65)
  - MacCurdy, H. M. (Box 66)
  - MacDonald, Alexander (Box 66)
  - MacDonald, Arthur, 1919-1930; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - MacDougal, D. T. (Daniel Trembly), 1899-1930; 6 folders (187 items) (Box 66)
    Bibliographical matters; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Genetics of plants -- Oenothera; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Shull, George Harrison; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1899-1903 (Box 66)
    - Folder 2, 1904 (Box 66)
    - Folder 3, 1905-1907 (Box 66)
    - Folder 4, 1908-1909 (Box 66)
    - Folder 5, 1910-1913 (Box 66)
    - Folder 6, 1914-1930 (Box 66)
  - MacDougall, Mary Stuart (Box 66)
  - MacDougall, William (Box 66)
  - Memoir on Gertrude Crotty Davenport, MacDowell, E. C. (Box 66)
  - MacFarland, Joseph (Box 66)
  - MacGillivray, Alexander D. (Box 66)
  - Macht, David J. (Box 66)
  - Mack Printing Company (Box 66)
  - Mack, E. L. (Box 66)
  - MacKaye, J. M. (Box 66)
  - MacKaye, Percy (Box 66)
  - Macker, LeRoy E. (Box 66)
  - Macklin, Madge Thurlow (Box 66)
  - MacKnight, Lydia E. (Box 66)
  - Maclaurin, Richard (Box 66)
  - Maclean, Mrs. M. D. (Box 66)
  - Macmillan Company, 1904-1936; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - MacMillan, Conway (Box 66)
  - Macon, George W. (Box 66)
  - Macy, Josiah, Jr., foundation (Box 66)
  - Macy, Leo (Box 66)
  - Macy, V. Everit (Box 66)
  - Macy, William A. (Box 66)
  - Maddock, George F. (Box 66)
  - Magers, S. D. (Box 66)
  - Maier, Hans W. (Box 66)
  - Mainardi, Athos (Box 66)
  - Mairs, G. Tylor (Box 66)
  - Major, Duncan K., Jr. (Box 66)
  - Malinowski, E. (Box 66)
  - Mallet, Bernard (Box 66)
  - Mallinson, Elizabeth L. (Box 66)
  - Mallock, Walter Scott (Box 66)
  - Malone, Dudley Field (Box 66)
  - Mann, A. R. (Box 66)
  - Manny, Frank A. (Box 67)
  - Manoilov's Sex Reaction (Box 67)
  - Mansell, Elizabeth V. H. (Box 67)
  - March, Lucien (Box 67)
  - Marchant, James (Box 67)
  - Marchlewski, J. (Box 67)
  - Mark, Edward Laurens, 1889-1943; 4 folders (236 items) (Box 67)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Graduate study; Harvard University; Human genetics; International Congress of Zoology; Publication; Recommendations -- MacDowell, E. Carleton; Recommendations -- Wright, Sewall; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1889-1904 (Box 67)
    - Folder 2, 1905-1921 (Box 67)
    - Folder 3, 1921-1939 (Box 67)
    - Folder 4, 1939-1943 (Box 67)
  - Marsh, C. Dwight (Box 67)
  - Marsh, M. C. (Box 67)
  - Marsh, R. O. (Box 67)
  - Marshall, Everett L. (Box 67)
  - Marshall, F. R. (Box 67)
  - Marshall, L. C. (Box 67)
  - Marston, Elizabeth H (Box 67)
  - Martin, Clifford F. (Box 67)
  - Martin, Mrs. John (Box 67)
  - Martin, Rudolf (Box 67)
  - Martz, Eugene W., 1929-1933; 3 folders (157 items) (Box 67)
    Anthropology; Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Letchworth Village
  - Mason, John Alden (Box 67)
  - Mason, Max (Box 67)
  - Master, Henry B. (Box 67)
  - Matheson, William J. (Mosquitoes) (Box 67)
  - Mathews, Albert (Box 67)
  - Mathews, Shailer (Box 67)
  - Matsuura, H. (Box 67)
  - Matthews, Mary L. (Box 67)
  - Mavor, James W. (Box 67)
  - May, Franklin H. (Box 67)
  - May, James V. (Box 67)
  - Mayer, Mrs. Alfred G. (Box 67)
  - Mayer, Edmund (Box 67)
  - Mayer, Harriet Hyatt (Box 67)
  - Mayer, Maria L. (Box 67)
  - Mayer, Paul P. (Box 67)
  - Mayers, D. C. (Box 67)
  - Mayo, Charles and William (Box 67)
  - Mayolez, O. & J. Audiarte (Box 67)
  - Mayor, Alfred G., 1895-1926; 9 folders (214 items) (Box 68)
    Biographical and personal data; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Graduate study; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Requests for aid in finding positions; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1895-1900 (Box 68)
    - Folder 2, 1901-1902 (Box 68)
    - Folder 3, 1903 (Box 68)
    - Folder 4, 1904-1907 (Box 68)
    - Folder 5, 1908-1911 (Box 68)
    - Folder 6, 1912-1915 (Box 68)
    - Folder 7, 1916-1921 (Box 68)
    - Biography, 2 folders (Box 68)
  - McBride, T. F. (Box 68)
  - McCallum, E. V. (Box 68)
  - McClendon, Jesse Francis (Box 68)
  - McCloy, C. H. (Box 68)
  - McClung, C. E. (Box 68)
  - McCord, William E. (Box 68)
  - McCormick, E. O. (Box 68)
  - McCracken, Isabel (Box 68)
  - McCue, C. (Box 68)
  - McCurdy, Arthur (Box 68)
  - McDougle, Ivan E. (Box 68)
  - McDowell, Charles (Box 68)
  - McGee, Anita Newcomb (Box 68)
  - McGeffin, C. G. (Box 68)
  - McGlachin, E. F. (Box 68)
  - McGlohon, J. D. (Box 68)
  - McGraw, Myrtle B., 1933-1936; 6 folders (Box 68)
    Anthropology; Embryology, developmental genetics
    - Folder 1, 1933 (Box 68)
    - Folder 2, 1934 (Box 68)
    - Folders 3-4, 1935; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Folders 5-6, 1936; 2 folders (Box 68)
  - McGregor, J. H. (Box 69)
  - McGrew, John B. (Box 69)
  - McGrew, T. F. (Box 69)
  - McIntosh, William Carmichael, 1902 (Box 69)
  - McKnight, H. Stewart (Box 69)
  - Mead, A. D. (Box 69)
  - Mead, Lucy I. (Box 69)
  - Meek, Elizabeth B. (Box 69)
  - Meerburg, G. F. Gezelle (Box 69)
  - Meiner, Ottilie (Box 69)
  - Melander, A. L. (Box 69)
  - Mellen, Frank (Box 69)
  - Meller, Ida M. (Box 69)
  - Melnick, Louis I. (Box 69)
  - Meloney, Marie M. (Box 69)
  - Meltzer, S. J. (Box 69)
  - Melvin, A. D. (Box 69)
  - Melvin, Lucille C. (Box 69)
  - Memmesheimer, Alois M. (Box 69)
  - Mendel, Lafayette B. (Box 69)
  - Mendel's memorial, 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Mendelson, H. (Box 69)
  - Menefee, Mrs. J. C. (Box 69)
  - Mengel, Levi W. (Box 69)
  - Menkin, Valy (Box 69)
  - Mensch, P. Calvin (Box 69)
  - Menschen und Menschenwerke (Box 69)
  - Merchant, Conley (Box 69)
  - Meredith, Mark (Box 69)
  - Merlin, J. R. (Box 69)
  - Merriam, C. Hart (Box 69)
  - Merriam, Charles E. (Box 69)
  - Merriam, G. and C., Co. (Box 69)
  - Merrill, A. A. (Box 69)
  - Merrill, Frederick J. H. (Box 69)
  - Merrill, John D. (Box 69)
  - Merriman, Willis E. (Box 69)
  - Merritt, Katherine (Box 69)
  - Merwin, Margaret S. (Box 69)
  - Mesnil, G. d'Ault du (Box 69)
  - Messner, Mathilde (Box 69)
  - Mestre, Aristides (Box 69)
  - Metcalf, C. L. (Box 69)
  - Metcalf, Haven (Box 69)
  - Metcalf, Maynard M. (Box 69)
  - Metz, C. W. (Charles W.), 1912-1936; 491 items (Box 69)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Evolution; Genetics -- Sciara; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Publication; Solicitations for support or contribution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Meyer, Adolf (Box 69)
  - Meyer, Julius (Box 69)
  - Mezes, Sidney E. (Box 69)
  - Micheli, Louis H. (Box 69)
  - Middleton, Austin R. (Box 69)
  - Miles, Walter R. (Box 69)
  - Millan, Ignacio (Box 69)
  - Millar, Ruth (Box 69)
  - Miller, Gerrit S., Jr. (Box 69)
  - Miller, Gerrit Smith (Box 69)
  - Miller, Louis (Box 69)
  - Miller, Nathan L. (Box 69)
  - Miller, O. R. (Box 69)
  - Miller, William G. (Box 69)
  - Milles, Bess Lloyd, 1923-1936; 3 folders (111 items) (Box 69)
    Cancer, chemotherapy; Graduate study; Human genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1923-1928 (Box 69)
    - Folder 2, 1929 (Box 69)
    - Folder 3, 1930-1936 (Box 69)
  - Milligan, J. W. (Box 69)
  - Minnich, D. E. (Box 70)
  - Minot, Charles S. (Box 70)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1 box (Box 71)
    - Assorted military camps, 1918 (Box 71)
    - Junior College Lectures (Box 71)
    - 1914: Pitcairn Colony; CDB personality analysis; Prisons in New South Wales (Box 71)
    - Pecten (Box 71)
  - Miscellaneous questions, 1934-1944; 7 folders (Box 70)
  - Mitchell, Walter R. (Box 70)
  - Mitsukusi, K. (Box 70)
  - Mjöen, Jon Alfred, 1916-1936; 3 folders (115 items) (Box 70)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; Mohr, Otto Louis; Political issues; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
    - Folder 1, 1916-1922 (Box 70)
    - Folder 2, 1923-1928 (Box 70)
    - Folder 3, 1929-1936 (Box 70)
  - Moe, Henry Allen (Box 70)
  - Moench, Gerard L. (Box 70)
  - Moenkhaus, William J. (Box 70)
  - Moens, H. M. Bernelot (Box 70)
  - Moffett, Thomas Clinton (Box 70)
  - Mohr, Otto L. (Box 70)
  - Mollison, T. H. (Box 70)
  - Monod, Léopold (Box 70)
  - Monroe Calculating Machine Co., Inc. (Box 70)
  - Monroe, Will S. (Box 70)
  - Montgomery, J. (Box 70)
  - Montgomery, Priscilla B. (Box 70)
  - Montgomery, Thomas H., Jr. (Box 70)
  - Moore, A. C. (Box 70)
  - Moore, Barrington (Box 70)
  - Moore, Eldon (Box 70)
  - Moore, Elizabeth Putnam (Box 70)
  - Moore, G. B. (Box 70)
  - Moore, William S. (Box 70)